Finding Aid for Sherwin T. Wine papers, 1930s-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Birmingham Temple
  - Activities
    - Anniversaries
      - Fortieth Anniversary
        - Correspondence, Agendas, and Planning Materials, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Ellen Bodner Study Group, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Health Day, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Monday Forum
      - 1971-1986 (Box 9)
      - 1995-2007 (Box 9)
    - Retirement of Sherwin T. Wine, 2003 (Box 9)
    - Other, 1990s-2000s (Box 9)
  - Administration
    - Congregational Ethics, undated (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 9)
    - Installation of Assistants to the Rabbi, circa 1990s (Box 9)
    - Installation of Officers and Trustees, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Membership Growth Report, undated (Box 9)
    - Music Director's Duties, undated (Box 9)
    - Pivnick Center for Humanistic Judaism Groundbreaking, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Statement of the Temple's Purpose and Identity, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Box 9)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 9)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 9)
    - 2002-2007 (Box 9)
  - Education
    - Adult Confirmation Course Materials, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 9)
    - Adult Education Committee Meetings, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Humanistic Judaism Class, 2002-2006 (Box 9)
    - Youth Education, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 9)
  - Newsletter (The Jewish Humanist)
    - Honorary Service, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Publication Checklists, 1997-2002 (Box 9)
    - 1981, 2003-2007 (Box 9)
  - Press Releases and Clippings, 1977-2003 (Box 10)
  - Rabbinical Duties
    - Dedication of the Torah, undated (Box 10)
    - Licenses to Solemnize Marriages, 1989-2006 (Box 10)
    - Marriage Records
      - 1956-1968 (Box 10)
      - 1968-1971 (Box 10)
      - 1971-1973 (Box 10)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 10)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 10)
      - 1975-1977 (Box 10)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 10)
      - 1980-1982 (Box 10)
      - 1982-1984 (Box 10)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 10)
      - 1990-1995 (Box 10)
      - 1995-2006 (Box 10)
    - Ordination of Tamara Kolton, 1999 (Box 10)
      (First ordained Humanistic Rabbi)
    - Sermons
      - 1960s, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 10)
      - 1963 (Box 10)
      - 1964 (Box 10)
      - 1965 (Box 10)
      - 1966 (Box 10)
      - 1977-1991 (Box 10)
      - Undated (Box 10)
  - Temple Services
    - Holidays, 1963-1964; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Remembrance Service, 1986 (Box 11)
    - Shabbat, 1998-2005 (Box 11)
    - Themed Topics
      - A-J, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 11)
      - L-R, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 11)
      - S-Z, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 11)
    - World Day, 1976-1980s (Box 11)
- Center for New Thinking
  The Center for New Thinking series documents Wine's involvement with the community forum he launched in 1976. Materials include administrative records (articles of incorporation, board meetings, financial information, and membership files), correspondence, publications, and event flyers (related to Center anniversaries, various weekly forums, seminars, etc.). This series also contains an index of the unarranged tapes in the Sound Recordings series.
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1976-1993 (Box 11)
  - Board of Advisors, 1980-2006 (Box 11)
  - Board Meetings, 1984-2004 (Box 11)
  - Clippings, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Community Cable Television Schedules and Information, 1994-2006 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1991-2007 (Box 11)
  - Events
    - Anniversaries, 1979-2007 (Box 11)
    - Classes, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
    - Library Construction and Opening, 2002-2003 (Box 11)
    - Saturday Forum, 1979-2006 (Box 11)
    - Saturday Seminar, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Sunday Alternative, 1998-2006 (Box 11)
    - Sunday Forum, 1982-2007 (Box 11)
    - Tuesday Forum, 1980-2000s (Box 11)
    - Thursday Forum, 2000s (Box 11)
    - Other, 1990-2004 (Box 11)
  - Financial Records
    - 1979-1985 (Box 11)
    - 1996-2005 (Box 11)
  - Membership Files, 1987-2004 (Box 12)
  - Memorials, 1988-1999 (Box 12)
  - Mission Statement, undated (Box 12)
  - Monographs, 1985-1989 (Box 12)
  - Newsletters
    - 1982-1985 (Box 12)
    - 1997-2007 (Box 12)
  - Newsletter Distribution Plans, 2004 (Box 12)
  - Tape Index for Recorded Lectures, 1977-2007 (Box 12)
  - Tax Exemption Information, 1994-2001 (Box 12)
  - Web Site Development, 1998-2001 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 12)
- Organizations
  The Organizations series is broken into eight subseries and reflects the many diverse groups with which Wine was involved in his lifelong quest to promote Humanistic Judaism and general humanist values.
  - Arts Foundation of Michigan
    The Arts Foundation of Michigan subseries documents Wine's support for the arts as the chair of its Scholarship Committee. In addition to materials related to Wine's committee, there are administrative records, an organizational history, and various reports.
    - Arts Michigan Merger, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Board Members, 1991-1995 (Box 12)
    - Bylaws and Committee Charters, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 12)
    - Creative Artist Grant Program, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Financial Records, 1992-1995 (Box 12)
    - Grant Information, 1985 (Box 12)
    - History of the Foundation, 1980s-1990 (Box 12)
    - Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Materials, 1987-1996 (Box 12)
    - Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    - Scholarship Committee Materials, 1981-1996 (Box 12)
    - Strategic Plan, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Clergy and Citizens United (CCU)
    The Clergy and Citizens United (CCU) subseries documents the group Wine helped found and its attempts to counter the religious right's definition of family values, introduction of school prayer initiatives, and other issues. This subseries contains materials related to CCU's American Values Institute as well as clippings, correspondence, administrative records, and position statements.
    - American Values Institute, 1995-1997 (Box 12)
    - Clippings, 1995-2001 (Box 12)
    - Constitution, 1995 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 12)
    - Events, 1997-2001 (Box 12)
    - Meetings, circa 2000s (Box 12)
    - Members, circa 1995 (Box 12)
    - Resource Materials for Issues, circa 1995 (Box 12)
    - Statements and Writings, 1995-2000 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1997-2000 (Box 12)
  - International Federation of Secular Humanistic Jews (IFSHJ)
    The International Federation of Secular Humanistic Jews (IFSHJ) subseries illustrates Wine's extensive involvement with Humanistic Judaism on the international scene. The subseries includes extensive information about the group's first conference, organizational bylaws, correspondence, and materials concerning the IFSHJ's North American branch (the North American Federation of Secular Humanistic Jews) and its activities as well as those of the Leadership Conference for Secular and Humanistic Jews.
    - Bylaws, undated (Box 12)
    - Clippings, 2004 (Box 12)
    - Conferences
      - 1986 (Box 12)
      - 1988-2006 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence, 1988-2006 (Box 12)
    - International Executive Committee, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Leadership Conference for Secular and Humanistic Jews, 1987-2002 (Box 12)
    - Newsletter, 1999 (Box 12)
    - North American Federation of Secular Humanistic Jews
      - Executive Committee, 1987 (Box 12)
      - First Biennial Meeting, 1987 (Box 12)
      - Mission Statement, 1987 (Box 12)
    - Press Releases, 1986 (Box 12)
  - International Institute for Secular Humanistic Judaism (IISHJ) (Box 13)
    The International Institute for Secular Humanistic Judaism (IISHJ) subseries highlights Wine's involvement in the creation and operation of Humanistic Judaism's main source of publications and leadership training. The subseries includes content related to the IISHJ's administration, educational activities (seminar listings, course catalogs, and its Leadership Program) and events (conferences, symposia, and colloquia) in addition to Wine's correspondence.
    - Academic Seminars, undated, 2001-2003 (Box 13)
    - Book Project, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
    - Brochures, undated, 2006 (Box 13)
    - Budget (proposed), 1986 (Box 13)
    - Catalog, undated (Box 13)
    - Clippings, 1995-1997 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence
      - Undated (Box 13)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
      - 1986, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - 1987-1994 (Box 13)
      - 2004-2007 (Box 13)
    - Events
      - Alpern Symposium on Religious Unity, 2003 (Box 13)
      - Annual Conference, 1998 (Box 13)
      - Colloquia, 1995-2007 (Box 13)
      - Colloquia Proceedings (publications)
        - 1995 (Box 13)
        - 1999 (Box 13)
        - 2001 (Box 13)
      - Jerusalem Seminar, 1995 (Box 13)
      - (Jeffrey) Sachs Lecture, 2005 (Box 13)
    - Goals and Projects, 1986 (Box 13)
    - Governance, 1985-1992 (Box 13)
    - Job Descriptions, 2003 (Box 13)
    - Leadership Program, 1984-2004 (Box 13)
    - Related Writings, undated (Box 13)
    - Tax Exemption Notice, 1986 (Box 13)
  - North American Committee for Humanism (NACH)
    The North American Committee for Humanism (NACH) subseries highlights Wine's role in creating and leading a confederation of six major humanist organizations. These files cover administrative activities (meetings, bylaws, financial records, etc.), clippings, correspondence, and publications in addition to documentation of the operation and educational activities of the NACH's graduate-level program at the Humanist Institute.
    - Administration
      - Annual Meetings, 1984-1987 (Box 13)
      - Articles of Incorporation, 1982-1983 (Box 13)
      - Board Meeting Agendas, Minutes, and Materials, 1983-2001 (Box 13)
      - Bylaws, 1983-1989 (Box 13)
      - Combined NACH/Humanist Institute Board Meeting, 2000 (Box 13)
      - Financial Records, 1989-1995 (Box 13)
      - IRS Audit Response, 1992 (Box 13)
      - Leadership Award, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
      - Leadership Conference, 1985-1986 (Box 13)
      - Membership Directory, 1991-1992 (Box 13)
      - Mission and Vision Statements, circa 2000 (Box 13)
        (Includes the NACH's five-year plan)
      - Organizing Meeting, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Clippings, 1985-1991 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence
      - 1982-1988 (Box 13)
      - 1989-1993 (Box 13)
    - Events (Box 14)
      - Conference Address ("Human Relations for the '90s"), circa 1990s (Box 14)
      - Humanist Weekend, 1987-1995 (Box 14)
      - Michigan Humanist Weekend, 1992 (Box 14)
      - Moscow Humanist/Atheist Dialogue, 1985-1989 (Box 14)
      - "Rebels with a Cause" (dramatic monologue), 1989 (Box 14)
      - Retirement of Sherwin T. Wine, 1992 (Box 14)
      - Twentieth Anniversary, 2002 (Box 14)
    - History, circa 1983 (Box 14)
    - The Humanist Institute
      - Accreditation, 1984 (Box 14)
      - Administration
        - Board of Governors, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
        - Board Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1991-1995 (Box 14)
        - Bylaws, undated (Box 14)
        - Contracts, 1985 (Box 14)
        - Curriculum, Schedules, and Course Offerings, 1987-1997 (Box 14)
        - Financial Records, 1987-2001 (Box 14)
        - Friends of the Humanist Institute Leadership Award, 1986 (Box 14)
        - Fundraising Activities, 1985-1989 (Box 14)
        - Library Remodeling, 1990 (Box 14)
        - Long Range Planning, circa 2006 (Box 14)
        - Mission and Direction, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
        - Paul Beattie Memorial Scholarship, 1990 (Box 14)
        - Staff Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1985-1992 (Box 14)
      - Background and History, 1982-1991 (Box 14)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box 14)
      - Directory, 2004 (Box 14)
      - Faculty Lists, Memoranda, and Curricula Vitae, 1985-1999 (Box 14)
      - Faculty Colloquia, 1987-1997 (Box 14)
      - Publications
        - Brochures, undated (Box 14)
        - Humanism Today (journal), 1991-1992 (Box 14)
        - Newsletters, 1984-1986 (Box 14)
        - Miscellaneous Writings, 1980s-1992 (Box 14)
      - Students
        - Application for Admission, undated (Box 14)
        - Class Rosters, 1985-1991 (Box 14)
        - First Class, 1984 (Box 14)
        - Graduates, 1983-1999 (Box 14)
        - Issues, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
    - Publications
      - The Best of Humanism (anthology), 1985-1986 (Box 14)
      - Brochure, undated (Box 14)
      - Newsletters and Mailings, 1983-2001 (Box 14)
    - Youth Groups, 1988-1992 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
  - Society for Humanistic Judaism (SHJ)
    The Society for Humanistic Judaism (SHJ) subseries contains correspondence, clippings, and educational materials as well as materials related to the first conference of Secular and Humanistic Jews.
    - Adult Education Seminar, undated (Box 14)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, circa 1980s (Box 14)
    - Background, undated (Box 14)
    - Conferences, 2001-2004 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence, 1988-2007 (Box 14)
    - First Conference of Secular and Humanistic Jews
      - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 14)
      - Photographs, 1981 (Box 14)
      - Publicity and Clippings, 1981-1984 (Box 14)
    - Humanistic Judaism Groups, 1997-2007 (Box 14)
    - Israel Trips, undated (Box 14)
    - Newsletters, 1973; 2006 (Box 14)
    - Songbook, undated (Box 14)
  - Voice of Reason (VOR)/Americans for Religious Liberty (ARL)
    The Voice of Reason (VOR)/Americans for Religious Liberty (ARL) subseries illustrates Wine's role in the organization and operation of a group intended to combat the rise of right-wing fundamentalism in the early 1980s. The files cover the organizations administration and activities as well as correspondence, clippings, and newsletters.
    - Activities, 1981-1987 (Box 14)
    - Administration
      - Advisory Board, 1982 (Box 14)
      - Articles of Incorporation and Certificate of Amendment, 1981; 1984 (Box 14)
      - Board of Directors, 1982-1985 (Box 14)
      - Bylaws and Organizational Rules, 1981-1983 (Box 14)
      - Chapters, 1982 (Box 14)
      - Coalitions, 1982 (Box 14)
      - Financial Contributions, 1981-1983 (Box 14)
      - Financial Records, 1981-1986 (Box 14)
      - Membership Cards, 1981-1982 (Box 14)
      - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1982-2003 (Box 14)
      - Merger with the Humanist Foundation, 2002 (Box 14)
      - Mission and Purpose, 2004 (Box 14)
        (letter from cofounder Edward Ericson)
      - Statement of Principles, circa 1982 (Box 14)
      - Tax Exemption Information, 1981 (Box 14)
    - Background and History, 1981-2000 (Box 15)
    - Clippings, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1983-2003 (Box 15)
    - Council of Organizations and Others for Educations About Parochiaid (CAP), 1983-1984 (Box 15)
    - Issues, 1981-1990 (Box 15)
    - Michigan Chapter Activities and Related Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 15)
    - Newsletters, Publications, and Mailings, 1981-1995 (Box 15)
    - Science Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
    - Speakers Bureau, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Other
    The Other subseries contains information related to the 27 other organizations with which Wine was involved (to varying degrees) over the course of his life. The contents are highly diverse and include religious, social, professional, and humanistic organizations; notable groups include the International Association of Humanist Educators, Counselors, and Leaders (restructured in 1993) and Scientists and Citizens United (founded by Wine not long before his untimely death).
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 2001-2007 (Box 15)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) of Michigan, Oakland County Branch, 2005 (Box 15)
    - American Ethical Union and Ethical Culture Societies, 1982-1984 (Box 15)
    - American Friends of Religious Freedom in Israel (AFRFI), 2005 (Box 15)
    - American Humanist Association (AHA), 1980-2007 (Box 15)
    - American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, Inc., 1989 (Box 15)
    - Association of Humanistic Rabbis (AHR), 1991-2007 (Box 15)
    - Center for Humanistic Studies, 1999 (Box 15)
    - Central Conference of American Rabbis, 1974-1982 (Box 15)
    - Conference on Liberal Religion (CLR)
      - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 15)
      - Meetings, Related Materials, Clippings, etc., 1985-1994 (Box 15)
      - Newsletters and Memoranda, 1985-1993 (Box 15)
    - Council for Democratic and Secular Humanism, 1980-1992 (Box 15)
    - Fellowship of Religious Humanists (FRH)
      - Board Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1980-1991 (Box 15)
      - Bylaws, 1968-1990 (Box 15)
      - Clippings, 1980 (Box 15)
      - Conferences, Annual Meetings, and Related Materials, 1968-1984 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1992 (Box 15)
      - Directories, 1980-1991 (Box 15)
      - Financial Records, 1992 (Box 15)
      - Future Planning Committee, 1980 (Box 15)
      - President's Reports and Memoranda, 1984-1992 (Box 15)
    - Gay and Lesbian Atheists and Humanists (GALAH), undated (Box 15)
    - Humanist Chaplaincy at Harvard, 2007 (Box 15)
    - Institute for Professional Clergy/Institute for Creative Religious Leadership, 1974-1976 (Box 15)
    - International Humanist and Ethical Union (IHEU)
      - Background and History, undated (Box 15)
      - Bylaws, Applications, etc., 1953-1992 (Box 15)
      - Correspondence, 1979-1992 (Box 15)
      - Directories, 1982-1993 (Box 15)
      - Events, 1978-1992 (Box 15)
      - International Survey on the Social and Legal Position of Humanists, undated (Box 15)
      - Proposed Resolution on Israeli-Palestinian Issue, 1988 (Box 15)
        (written by Sherwin T. Wine)
      - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1984-1992 (Box 15)
      - Member Organizations, 1982-1997 (Box 15)
      - Newsletters and Journals, 1980-2001 (Box 15)
    - International Association of Humanist Educators, Counselors, and Leaders (IAHECL) (Box 16)
      - Annual Reports, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Associated Activities and Groups, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Background and History, 1989-1992 (Box 16)
      - Biennial Seminars, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Board of Directors and Officers, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Board Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Constitution, undated (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Distinguished Leadership Award, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
      - Decentralization and Restructuring, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Financial Records, 1988-1992 (Box 16)
      - Humanist Education, undated (Box 16)
      - Membership, 1989 (Box 16)
      - Professional Code, undated (Box 16)
      - Publications
        - The European Humanist (journal), 1994 (Box 16)
        - The Humanist Professional (journal), 1989-1991 (Box 16)
        - IAHECL News (newsletter) and Mailings, 1990-1992 (Box 16)
      - Statements on Issues, undated (Box 16)
    - Michigan Board of Rabbis, 1998-2006 (Box 16)
    - Michigan Coalition of Secular and Humanistic Jews, 1984-1989 (Box 16)
    - The National Jewish Center for Learning and Leadership (CLAL), 1989 (Box 16)
    - The New Group, 1983-2003 (Box 16)
    - Progressive Zionists, 1987 (Box 16)
    - Scientists and Citizens United
      - Background, 2007 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 16)
      - Issues, 2006-2007 (Box 16)
      - Meetings and Events, 2006-2007 (Box 16)
      - Press Releases and Writings, 2006-2007 (Box 16)
      - Speakers Bureau, 2006-2007 (Box 16)
    - Secular Jewish Community Center, 1999 (Box 16)
    - Triangle Foundation, 1993-2002 (Box 16)
    - Unitarian Universalist Association of Congregations, 2007 (Box 16)
    - United Jewish Communities
      - 1999 (Box 16)
      - 2001 (Box 16)
- Public Appearances
  The Public Appearances series contains announcements, programs, and related correspondence to the numerous speaking engagements held by Wine around the metropolitan Detroit area. This series is unarranged.
  - Announcements, programs, and related correspondence, 1980s-2000s (Box 17)
    (unarranged)
- Subject Files
  The Subject Files series contains Wine's personal files on a variety of topics ranging from the American Constitution to Objectivism and includes Wine's notes and collected materials. Of particular note are a file of Wine's personal heroes and a manuscript letter written by Benjamin Disraeli.
  - American Constitution, 1950s; 1977-1979 (Box 18)
  - Anti-Semitism, undated (Box 18)
  - Anthropology, 1970-1979 (Box 18)
  - Birobidzhan, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Capitalism, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Cartoons, 1977-2000 (Box 18)
  - Censorship, undated (Box 18)
  - Children's Stories, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Communism, undated (Box 18)
  - Counter Culture, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Disraeli, Benjamin, 1864 (Box 18)
  - Drama, undated (Box 18)
  - Euthanasia, 1978-1982 (Box 18)
  - Family, 1967-1999 (Box 18)
  - Flat Iron Buildings, undated (Box 18)
  - Friends
    - Creativity, 1998 (Box 18)
    - Personal, undated (Box 18)
  - Futurism, 1956 (Box 18)
  - Hebrew-English Dictionary, undated (Box 18)
  - Hebrew Readings, undated (Box 18)
  - Heroes, 1973-1998 (Box 18)
  - Hershman, Abraham, undated (Box 18)
  - Himmelhoch Family, 1994-1996 (Box 18)
  - Holocaust, undated (Box 18)
  - Homosexuality, 1970s-1980s (Box 18)
  - Humor, 1998-1999 (Box 18)
  - Individualism, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Middle East, 1978-1979 (Box 18)
  - Objectivism, 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Punishment, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Rabbis, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Reconstructionism, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Readings, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 18)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin, 1945 (Box 18)
  - Sex, 1976-1980 (Box 18)
  - Skinner, B.F., 1967 (Box 18)
  - Theology, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 18)
- Card Files
  The Card Files series contains the various card files used by Wine in his professional life. The Administration cards contain contact information, overviews of Birmingham Temple activities and events, and summaries of office procedures. Reference Materials include Wine's notes from his readings and research and are arranged alphabetically by personal name, topic, or organization. Lectures contain outlines of talks and were used by Wine at the Birmingham Temple, the Center for New Thinking, and various conferences, forums, events, etc. There are five distinct groupings of lecture materials and these range from the unarranged to the carefully alphabetized. Funerals and Eulogies were used by Wine at memorial services throughout his career as a rabbi.
  - Administration, including contact information, Birmingham Temple activities, and office procedures, 1980s-2000s (Box 19)
  - Reference Materials: Notes from readings and other research, arranged by personal name, topic, or organization, undated
    - A-G (Box 20)
    - H-Rei (Box 21)
    - Rel-Z (Box 22)
  - Lectures: Outlines of talks delivered at the Birmingham Temple, Center for New Thinking, and various conferences, events, etc.
    - 1970s-1980s (Box 23)
      (loosely alphabetized)
    - 1970s-2000s (Box 24)
    - 1980s-2000s (Box 25)
      (A-Z)
    - 1990s-2000s (Box 26)
  - Various Lecture and Reference Materials, 1960s-1990s (Box 27)
  - Funerals and Eulogies, 1950s-2000s (Box 28)
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings series consists mainly of cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking. While these materials are unarranged, a tape index in the Center for New Thinking series provides a detailed list of subject matter and dates. This series also contains additional recordings (on compact disc) of Wine speaking.
  - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 29)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 30)
      (continued)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 31)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 32)
    - Cassettes of various lectures delivered at the Center for New Thinking, 1970s-2007 (Box 33)